{
  "status":"1",
  "message":"success",
  "quiz": [
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "Who discovered the phenomenon called Gravitation",
      "options": [
        "Galileo",
        "Dalton",
        "Johannes Kepler",
        "Sir Isaac Newton"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Sir Isaac Newton"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "Which of the following involves Centripetal Force",
      "options": [
        "The Centre of Circular Motion",
        "Object in Circular Motion",
        "Object in Linear Motion",
        "Perpendicular to Linear Motion"
      ],
      "correctAns": "The Centre of Circular Motion"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The Gravitational Force acts on which direction ?",
      "options": [
        "Fly off in a Horizontal direction",
        "it's in vertically downward direction",
        "is at an angle to the vertical direction",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correctAns": "it's in vertically downward direction"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The Inverse Square Law of gravitation was formulated by",
      "options": [
        "Newton",
        "Brahe",
        "Cavendish",
        "Kepler"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Newton"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The circular motion of planets around the sun is due to ………………",
      "options": [
        "Circular force",
        "Centripetal Force",
        "Linear force",
        "Centrifugal force"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Centripetal Force"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The center of mass of any object having uniform density is at its ",
      "options": [
        "Orthocenter",
        "Incenter",
        "Centroid",
        "Circumcenter"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Centroid"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The amount of matter present in the object is called ………………",
      "options": [
        "Mass",
        "Substance",
        "Weight",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Mass"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The acceleration due to gravity(g) acts along …...... direction",
      "options": [
        "Vertically downward",
        "Towards the center of earth",
        "Away from the center of earth",
        "Vertically Upward"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Towards the center of earth"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The Unit of Force is ______________",
      "options": [
        "Newton",
        "Kilogram",
        "Joule",
        "m/sec^2"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Newton"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The potential energy of an object of mass “m” and at a height “h” from the surface of the earth is ………………",
      "options": [
        "1/2 mv^2",
        "Zero",
        "mgh",
        "None of These"
      ],
      "correctAns": "mgh"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The energy stored in an object, because of its position is called ……………………",
      "options": [
        "Sun's Energy",
        "Potential Energy",
        "Interior Energy",
        "Kinetic Energy"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Potential Energy"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The earth gravitational force (g) varies with ………………",
      "options": [
        "Change with height",
        "Change with Depth",
        "Change along the Surface of earth",
        "All of the Above"
      ],
      "correctAns": "All of the Above"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The earth gravitational force on communication satellite is ………………",
      "options": [
        "9.7 m/sec^2",
        "9.8 m/sec^2",
        "0.2 m/sec^2",
        "8.7 m/sec^2"
      ],
      "correctAns": "0.2 m/sec^2"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The orbit of a planet is an ellipse with the sun at one of the foci is  according to ",
      "options": [
        "Kepler’s 1st Law",
        "Newton’s 2nd Law",
        "Kepler’s 2st Law",
        "Newton’s 1nd Law"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Kepler’s 1st Law"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "Which law states that “every object attracts every other object”? ",
      "options": [
        "Brahe's Law of Gravitation",
        "Kepler's Law of Gravitation",
        "Newtons Law of Gravitation",
        "Cavendish's Law of Gravitaiton"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Newtons Law of Gravitation"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The point at which, the total mass of the object concentrate is  …………………",
      "options": [
        "Center of mass",
        "Uniform density",
        "Geometrical center",
        "Center of gravity"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Center of mass"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The level of water in the sea changes because of the …………",
      "options": [
        "Gravitational force exerted by both earth and moon",
        "Gravitational force exerted by moon",
        "Gravitational force exerted by earth",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Gravitational force exerted by moon"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "Which among the following is Vector quantity ? ",
      "options": [
        "Force",
        "Work",
        "Acceleration",
        "All"
      ],
      "correctAns": "All"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The radius of earth is minimum at ",
      "options": [
        "Poles",
        "Equator",
        "None of the above",
        "Between equator and poles"
      ],
      "correctAns": "Poles"
    },
    {
      "QorL": "Q",
      "question": "The effect of Doubling the distance between the object on G value ",
      "options": [
        "G becomes half",
        "G decreases by a factor of 4",
        "G is Doubled",
        "No Change in G Value"
      ],
      "correctAns": "G decreases by a factor of 4"
    }
  ]
}
